A Finding Aid to the Fendrick Gallery Records, 1952-2001, in the Archives of American Art AAA.fendgall
Archives of American Art
- Subject Files, 1952, 1960-2001, undated; Series 6; (Box 73-88, OV 115, 116; 15.5 linear feet)
  - Photorealism, 1987-1988 (Box 86)
  - Pop Art Posters, 1961-1974, undated (Box 86)
  - Postcards by Artists, 1974-1978 (Box 86)
  - Posters, 1964-1987, undated; (2 folders) (Box 86)
  - Print Buyers, 1988-1990, undated (Box 86)
  - Printmaking, 1978-1984 (Box 86)
  - Sculpture, 1974-1985, undated (Box 86)
  - Sculpture Artists (Box 86)
    - A-H, 1974-1987, undated; (3 folders) (Box 86)
    - Kadisman-Katzen, 1972-1980, undated (Box 86)
    - Kelly, 1984-1985; (2 folders) (Box 87)
    - Kessler-Kozloff, 1974-1983 (Box 87)
    - L-Z, 1969-1985, undated; (4 folders) (Box 87)
  - Southwestern Art, 1975, undated (Box 87)
  - Still Lifes, 1971, 1980-1984, undated (Box 87)
  - Still Life Artists, A-Y, 1975-1985, undated; (3 folders) (Box 87)
  - Stolen Artwork, 1983-1989 (Box 87)
  - Tapestries and Banners, 1968-1988, undated; (5 folders) (Box 87)
  - 35th Venice Biennale, 1970 (Box 88)
  - Thomas Hart Benton Sale, 1997 (Box 88)
  - Toys for Adults and Children, 1972, 1979, undated (Box 88)
  - Trompe L'oeil, 1980-1984 (Box 88)
  - Washington Art Dealers Association, 1987-1996, undated (Box 88)
  - Washington Artists, 1983-1987 (Box 88)
  - Water in Art, 1980-1990, undated (Box 88)
  - Watercolor Artists, 1977-1983, undated (Box 88)
  - Wearable Art, 1976-1986, undated; (3 folders) (Box 88)
  - Wood, 1977-1985, undated (Box 88)
  - Wood Artists, A-Y, 1975-1988, circa 1990?, undated; (4 folders) (Box 88)
  - Oversized Catalogs (Gallery and Museum), 1988-1989 (Box OV 115)
  - Oversized Catalogs (Individual Artists), G-M, 1967-1999 (Box OV 116)
  - Oversized Catalogs (Individual Artists), S, 1960-1998 (Box OV 116)
- Administrative and Financial Files, 1960-2001, undated; Series 7; (Box 88-106; 17.5 linear feet)
  Administrative and financial records of both the Barbara Fendrick Gallery (New York) and the Fendrick Gallery (Washington, D.C.), as well as files that document Barbara Fendrick's role as art consultant, appraiser, lecturer, exhibition juror, and guest curator. Found are numerous inventory cards, insurance records, consignment files, general correspondence, lists, loan files, notebooks, real estate files, card files on artists and clients, and history files. Of particular interest are the Day Books/Dailies maintained by the New York gallery staff consisting of entries and notes regarding prospective clients and their interests. The Telephone Log Books contain details of telephone conversations with artists, clients, dealers, and other art professionals.
  Series 7 also houses the financial records of both galleries, including financial statements, invoices, expenses, accounts, and tax records.
  - Advertisements (See also Box 106, sol), 1982-1997, undated (Box 88)
  - Air Transport and Shipping Estimates, 1979-1984, undated (Box 88)
  - Application for Patent for Picture Frame, 1952-2001 (Box 88)
  - Appointment Books, 1985-1986; (2 folders) (Box 88)
  - Appointment Books, 1987-1991; (6 folders) (Box 89)
  - Art Appraisals, 1974-1992, undated; (6 folders) (Box 89)
  - Art Consultancy and Acquisitions, 1975-1994, undated (Box 89)
  - Art Consultants, 1983-1985, undated (Box 89)
  - Artists' Slides Registries, 1987-1989, undated (Box 89)
  - Calendars (See also Box 106), 1979-1983 (Box 89)
  - Card Files, Artists, 1977-1991, undated (Box 90)
  - Card Files, Clients, Local, A-S, 1972-1991, undated; (3 shoe boxes) (Box 90)
  - Card Files, Clients, Local, T-Z, 1972-1991, undated (Box 91)
  - Card Files, Clients, National and International, A-Z, 1972-1991, undated; (2 shoe boxes) (Box 91)
  - Clients Looking to Buy, 1985-1992 (Box 92)
  - Computer Disk Log Book, 1986-1991 (Box 92)
  - Computer Disks, 1988-1991, undated; (2 folders) (Box 92)
  - Consignment Forms, undated (Box 92)
  - Consignments, 1971-1999, undated; (2 folders) (Box 92)
  - Contacts, 1987-1990, undated (Box 92)
  - Correspondence (Box 92)
    - Corporate, 1988-1991 (Box 92)
    - General, 1962, 1971-1991; (11 folders) (Box 92)
    - General, 1992-2001, undated; (6 folders) (Box 93)
    - Japanese Dealers and Clients, 1988-1990, undated (Box 93)
    - National Endowment for the Arts letters, 1990 (Box 93)
    - New York Gallery Opening, 1988 (Box 93)
    - Press Letters, 1989-1991 (Box 93)
    - Resale Inquiries, 1984-1993, undated; (3 folders) (Box 93)
  - Day Books/Dailies (Box 93)
    - Barbara Fendrick Gallery, 1987-1991; (2 folders) (Box 93)
    - Fendrick Gallery, 1978-1984; (2 folders) (Box 93)
    - Fendrick Gallery, 1984-1992; (3 folders) (Box 94)
    - Paley, Albert, 1983-1990 (Box 94)
  - Frame Orders, circa 1975-1990; (2 bound volumes) (Box 94)
  - Gallery History, 1987-1991, undated (Box 94)
  - Greensted, Lisa, Fraud Case Involving, 1975, 1992-1995, undated (Box 94)
  - Guest Books, 1984-1987 (Box 94)
  - Installation Forms, undated (Box 94)
  - Insurance (Box 94)
    - Flather & Perkins, Inc., 1986-1997 (Box 94)
    - Huntington T. Block, 1986-1994; (3 folders) (Box 94)
    - 1983 Flood Damage, 1983-1984; (5 folders) (Box 95)
    - Theft at New York Gallery, 1988-1989, undated (Box 95)
    - Workman's Compensation Policy, 1992-1993 (Box 95)
  - Inventory (Box 95)
    - Book Art (Box 95)
    - General, 1992 (Box 95)
    - Missing Artwork, 1979-1981 (Box 95)
  - Inventory Cards (Box 95)
    - 1966-1969;1970; 1971, Albers-Nevelson, 1966-1971; (shoe box) (Box 95)
    - 1971, Oldenburg-Wesselmann; 1972; Albers-Ruscha, 1971-1972; (shoe box) (Box 95)
    - 1972, Sander-Youngerman; 1973-June 1974, Albers-Quilts, 1972-1974; (shoe box) (Box 95)
    - 1973-June 1974, Rauschenberg-Youngerman;1973-June 1974, Native American Items; July 1974-June 1975, 1973-1975; (shoe box) (Box 96)
    - July 1975-June 1976; July 1975-June 1976, Books; July 1975-June 1976, Folk Art; July 1976-June 1977, Albers-Stewart, 1975-1977; (shoe box) (Box 96)
    - July 1976-June 1977, Stovall-Youkeles; July 1977-June 1979, 1976-1979; (shoe box) (Box 96)
    - July 1979-June 1980; July 1980-June 1981, 1979-1981; (shoe box) (Box 96)
    - July 1981-June 1982; July 1982-June 1983; 1984-June 1986, 1981-1986; (shoe box) (Box 96)
    - July 1986-June 1987; July 1987-June 1988; July 1988-June 1989; July 1989-June 1990, 1986-1989; (shoe box) (Box 96)
    - July 1990-1996, (shoe box) (Box 97)
    - Notes, 1972-1973, undated (Box 97)
  - Invoices (Box 97)
    - Barbara Fendrick Gallery, 1988-1991; (3 folders) (Box 97)
    - Fendrick Gallery, 1979-Nov. to Dec. 1981; (7 folders) (Box 97)
    - Fendrick Gallery, Jan. to June 1982-July to Dec. 1989; (17 folders) (Box 98)
    - Fendrick Gallery, Jan. to June 1990-1993; (4 folders) (Box 99)
  - Juries and Lectures, 1974-2001, undated (Box 99)
  - Lawsuit Involving Lichtenstein Print, 1972, 1990 (Box 99)
  - Letters of Recommendation, 1987-1991 (Box 99)
  - Lists (Box 99)
    - Additions to Mailing Lists, 1989-1998, undated; (2 folders) (Box 99)
    - Albert Paley Exhibition Mailing List, 1991 (Box 99)
    - Barbara Fendrick Gallery Mailing List, 1989-1990 (Box 99)
    - Craft Mailing List, 1989 (Box 99)
    - ERPF List by Zip Code, undated (Box 99)
    - Exhibition Price Lists, circa 1973-1996, undated (Box 99)
    - Fendrick Gallery Mailing List, 1989-1991; (2 folders; see Box 106) (Box 99)
    - Museums Mailing List, 1988-1991, undated (Box 99)
    - New York Gallery Opening Exhibition Mailing List, 1989 (Box 99)
    - Potential Clients, 1983-1999, undated (Box 99)
    - Press Mailing Lists, 1989-1990, undated (Box 99)
    - Print Prices, 1970, 1985-1991, undated (Box 99)
    - State and County Art Agencies, 1978, 1989-1992, undated; (2 folders) (Box 99)
  - Loans (Box 99)
    - Art-In-Embassies Program, 1982-1993, undated (Box 99)
    - Art for Exhibitions, 1973-1990; (2 folders) (Box 99)
    - Art for Exhibitions, 1991-1994, undated; (2 folders) (Box 100)
    - Photographs and slides, 1974-1991; (4 folders) (Box 100)
    - Miscellaneous Notes, 1985-1992, undated (Box 100)
  - Notebooks (Box 100)
    - Notes on Albert Paley Projects, 1986-1991 (Box 100)
    - Notes on Albert Paley Project in Atlanta, 1990 (Box 100)
    - Notes on Albert Paley Projects in Texas/Georgia, circa 1976 (Box 100)
    - Notes on Meetings with Raymond Kaskey, 1993-1994 (Box 100)
    - Notes on Trips to Florida/Texas/Atlanta, 1980-1984 (Box 100)
    - Notes on William Dusenbery/Sam Gilliam Projects, 1992 (Box 100)
    - Notes Written by Nicole Jundanian, circa 1991-1992 (Box 100)
    - Untitled, undated (Box 100)
  - Print Council of America Certificate (sign; see Box 106) (Box 100)
  - Publicity (Box 100)
    - Articles About Fendrick Galleries, 1962-1990, undated; (2 folders) (Box 100)
    - Gallery Newsletters, 1971-1990, undated; (2 folders) (Box 100)
    - Photographs, circa 1971-1992, undated (Box 100)
    - Press Releases, 1977-1988, undated (Box 100)
  - Real Estate (Box 101)
    - New York City, 568 Broadway, 1986-1988 (Box 101)
    - New York City, 216 LaFayette St., 1987-1990, undated (Box 101)
    - Search for New Gallery Space, 1984-1986, undated; (2 folders) (Box 101)
    - Washington, D.C., 3059 M St., NW, 1977-1989, undated (Box 101)
    - Washington, D.C., 1710 Connecticut Ave., N.W., 1996 (Box 101)
  - Resumes (Box 101)
    - Fendrick, Barbara, 1993, undated (Box 101)
    - Gallery Applicants, 1986-1990, undated (Box 101)
  - Shipping, 1988-1991, undated; (2 folders) (Box 101)
  - Telephone Log Books (Box 101)
    - Barbara Fendrick Gallery, 1987-1990; (3 folders) (Box 101)
    - Fendrick Gallery, 1976-2000; (5 folders) (Box 101)
    - Fendrick Gallery, 1976-2000; (15 folders) (Box 102)
    - Fendrick Gallery, 1976-2000; (6 folders) (Box 103)
    - Gilliam, Sam/Kaskey, Raymond, 1994-1995 (Box 103)
    - Paley, Albert, 1991-1993 (Box 103)
    - Real Estate, 1995 (Box 103)
    - South American Trip, 1996 (Box 103)
  - Bank Loans, 1972-1979 (Box 104)
  - Employees' Salaries, 1983-1986 (Box 104)
  - End-of-Year Accounts, 1987-1995; (7 folders) (Box 104)
  - Expenses (Box 104)
    - Barbara Fendrick Gallery, 1989-1991 (Box 104)
    - Fendrick Gallery (See also Box 105), 1977-1978 (Box 104)
  - Bound Financial Statements, 1974-1991; (4 folders) (Box 104)
  - Gross Sales and Commissions, 1981-1983, 1989-1990 (Box 104)
  - Ledger Book, 1960-1970; (2 folders) (Box 104)
  - Money Market Account, 1988-1991 (Box 104)
  - Petty Cash, 1974, 1990 (Box 104)
  - Taxes (Box 104)
    - District of Columbia, 1972, 1992-1995 (Box 104)
    - Federal, 1969, 1988-1997; (2 folders) (Box 104)
    - New York, 1989-1992 (Box 104)
    - Refunds, 1985-1989 (Box 104)
    - 1099 Forms, 1991-1993 (Box 104)
    - Virginia, 1991-1994 (Box 104)
    - W-2 Forms, 1983-1986, 1991-1994 (Box 104)
  - Financial Records, Expenses, Fendrick Gallery, 1991-1995 (Box 105 (pam))
  - Oversized Administrative Records (Box 106 (sol))
    - Calendars, 1977-1978, 1984-1986 (Box 106 (sol))
    - Fendrick Gallery Mailing Lists, 1989, 1991; (2 folders) (Box 106 (sol))
    - Print Council of America Certificate, undated (Box 106 (sol))